The Victor D'Amico Papers
The Museum of Modern Art, Publisher
- Series XI. Printed Materials, 1936-1995
  - Catalogues and reprints, 1966, 1967, 1970; "Art in kindergartens in Japan” by Lois Lord,Young Children; program for symposium "Japanese Children's Art and Literature,” San Francisco; directory "Spaces for the performing arts,” City of New York; "Ten years poetry and painting" by Carolyn Tyson (inscribed to Victor and Mabel D'Amico) (Box 67, Folder XI.15)
  - Catalogues of art education books, 1967-1968; From publishers including Reinhold, International Textbook Co. (Box 67, Folder XI.16)
  - Reprints of works by A.H. Maslow, 1968; "Goals of a humanistic education,”Esalen Papers; "A holistic approach to creativity,” Seventh National Research Conference on Creativity (Box 67, Folder XI.17)
  - Clippings, 1969, 1970, 1973, 1978; Includes "Genius: What is it? Who has it,”Vogue; "New, newer, newest",The New York Times; "Life roundtable on modern art,”LIFE Magazine; "Passing mutely before a painting to genuflect really turns me off,”Christian Science Monitor; re: Edith Frankel art exhibition in Southampton, NY (Box 67, Folder XI.18)
  - Inventory of books/publications, [1970s]; Handwritten lists of books (alphabetical by title, author, and organized by subject) with bookshelf designations (Box 67, Folder XI.19)
  - Think Magazine, March-April, May-June 1970; Two issues (Box 67, Folder XI.20)
  - Brochures, 1970; High Museum of Art, Associated Councils of the Arts (Box 67, Folder XI.21)
  - Reports and program, 1970-1972; "Report to the President" and "Strategies for implementation,” 1970 White House Conference on Children; "Popular culture, the arts, and education,” Maxine Green, Institute for the Study of Art in Education; National Association of Art Educators conference program (Box 67, Folder XI.22)
  - Art 1 Meaning Method and Media;Art 5 Meaning Method and Media, by Hubbard and Rose, 1972; Books published by Benefic Press (Box 67, Folder XI.23)
  - Clippings, reprint, 1972, 1978, undated; Includes Art Idea Book; "Design for Change,”The Art Museum as Educator, on the evolution of MoMA's education programs (Box 67, Folder XI.24)
  - Writings on art education, and letter in response by D'Amico, 1974, 1978; Includes "A plague on all your houses,”Art Education; excerpt from The Art Museum as Educator (Box 67, Folder XI.25)
  - New York State Art Teachers Association, 1975-1995; Conference programs, bulletins (Box 67, Folder XI.26)
  - "50 years of humanizing the arts" in Roundtable Reports, publication of the Museum Education Roundtable, 1980; Profile of D’Amico by Doris Lerman, excerpted from exhibition catalogue for eponymous exhibition at Guild Hall, East Hampton (see also Subseries X.A) (Box 67, Folder XI.27)
  - Clipping, May 13, 1984; "Diane Arbus: Her vision, life, and death,”The New York Times Magazine, by Patricia Bosworth. Arbus had been a student of D’Amico's at Ethical Culture Fieldston School (Box 67, Folder XI.28)
  - Conference presentation, March 2, 1991; "Victor D'Amico: A Legend and a Legacy,” Dr. Prabha Sahasrabudhe, University Council for Art Education Conference, MoMA (Box 67, Folder XI.29)
Box and Folder List
File numbers marked by an asterisk (*) indicate oversize material that has been separated to the end of the collection.
Researchers should include the asterisk when issuing a request for such material.
I 1-4, 6-19 1
II.A 1-20 2
II.A 21-31, 41-46 3
II.B 2-10 3
II.B 11-38 4
II.B 39-62 5
II.B 63-85 6
II.B 86-94 7
III.A 1-9 7
III.A 10-13 8
III.B 1-10 8
III.C 1-6, 8-10, 13-19 9
III.C 20-29 10
III.C 30-32, 35-41 11
III.C 42-52 12
III.C 53-72 13
III.C 73-82, 88 14
III.C 89-95 15
III.C 96-107 16
IV.A.i 1-4 16
IV.A.i 6-14, 16, 18 17
IV.A.i 19, 20, 23, 25-32 18
IV.A.ii 2,3 18
IV.A.ii 4-8 19
IV.A.iii 3-5 19
IV.A.iv 2-4, 6-12 19
IV.A.iv 13-16, 18 20
IV.A.v 1-12 20
IV.A.vi 1 20
IV.A.vi 5-10, 12-24 21
IV.A.vii 1-6 22
IV.A.vii 7-19, 21 23
IV.B 1-4 23
IV.B 5-8 24
IV.C 3-18 24
V 1-5, 7-11 25
V 12-27 26
V 28-35 27
V 36, 38-61 28
V 62-79 29
V 80-89, 91-100 30
V 101-127 31
V 128-152 32
V 153-159, 161 33
VI 1-7 33
VI 8-24 34
VI 25-44 35
VI 45-54 36
VI 55-70 37
VI 71-87 38
VI 88-98 39
VI 99-107 40
VII 1-3 40
VII 4-8 41
VII 9-13 42
VII 14-21 43
VII 22, 24-34 44
VII 35-49 45
VII 50-59 46
VII 60-62, 64-65 47
VIII.A 1-7 47
VII 63 48
VIII.A 8-25 49
VIII.A 26-43 50
VIII.A 44-46 51
VIII.A 47-50 52
VIII.B 1-8 52
VIII.B 9-15 53
VIII.C 1-9 54
VIII.C 10-18 55
VIII.C 19-25 56
VIII.C 26-32 57
VIII.C 33, 36-42 58
VIII.C 43-49 59
IX 1-12 59
IX 13-31 60
IX 32-42 61
IX 43-55 62
IX 56-62 63
X.A 1-8, 10-12 63
X.A 13-25 64
X.A 26-28, 30-35 65
X.B 1,5,7,10 65
XI 1-3, 6-13 66
XI 14-29 67
I 5* 68
II.A 32*-34* 68
II.B 1* 68
II.A 35*-40* 69
II.B 1* 69
III.C 11*, 12*, 33*, 34*, 87* 70
IV.A.iv 5*, 17* 70
IV.A.vi 2* 70
IV.A.vii 20* 70
V 6*, 160* 71
VII 23* 71
X.A 9* 71
X.B 2*, 3*, 6*, 8*, 9* 71
XI 4*, 5* 71
III.C 7*, 85*, 87* 72
IV.A.i 15*, 17*, 21*, 22*, 24* 72
III.C 83* 73
IV.A.iii 2* 73
IV.A.iv 1* 73
IV.A.vi 3*, 4*, 11* 73
IV.C 1* 73
V 37* 73
VIII.C 34* 73
X.A 29* 73
X.B 4* 73
III.C 84* Flat file 2-2
IV.A.i 5* Flat file 2-2
IV.A.ii 1* Flat file 2-2
IV.A.iii 1* Flat file 2-2
IV.C 2* Flat file 2-2
V 90* Flat file 2-2
VIII.C 35* Flat file 2-2